The Fog of War is a documentary, tv movie,
history film directed by Errol Morris.
Using archival footage, cabinet conversation recordings, and an interview of the 85-year-old Robert McNamara, The Fog of War depicts his life, from working as a WWII
whiz-kid military officer, to being the Ford Motor Company's president, to managing the Vietnam War as defense secretary for presidents Kennedy and Johnson.
Self, played by Robert McNamara.
Self (uncredited), played by Errol Morris.
Self (archive footage) (uncredited), played by Fidel Castro.
Self (archive footage) (uncredited), played by Barry Goldwater.
Self (archive footage) (uncredited), played by John F. Kennedy.
Self (archive footage) (uncredited), played by Nikita Khrushchev.
The Fog of War: Eleven Lessons from the Life of Robert S.
McNamara is a 2003 American documentary film about
the life and times of former U.S.
Secretary of Defense Robert McNamara, illustrating his
observations of the nature of modern warfare.
It was directed by Errol Morris and features an original score by Philip Glass.
The title derives from the military concept of the "fog of war", which refers
to the difficulty of making decisions in the midst of conflict.
The film was screened out of competition at the 2003 Cannes Film Festival and won the Academy Award for Best
Documentary Feature and the Independent Spirit Award for Best Documentary Feature of 2003.
In 2019, it was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United States National
Film Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of vietnam, politics, biography,
historical figure, historical society.